In this video, we're going to go over
screen space reflections, which is a
topic that deserves a little bit more time
for
discussion. Screen space reflections allow
you to calculate reflections from the
scene in real time without needing to use
reflection probes, which we cover in the
next module. This is a very intense
effect, so reflection probes are the more
performant option, but screen space
reflections are an option if you're
very high-end devices. You're going to see
this effect mostly on water,
metallics, and other reflective
materials. Once we've added screen space
reflections onto our volume,
let's take a look at it in
action. Right now in our evening A scene
here, the main thing that uses
reflections are these air ducts above
us. If I were to disable these reflection
probes, we can see the
color of these air ducts completely
change, since after all these ducts are
metallic, and they reflect the light from
the office around it.
These reflection probes approximate the
amount of light that the metallic air
are going to give off. Let's say I want to
completely do away with reflection probes
and have these use screen space
reflections to approximate their
reflection. What we can do is we can come
over to the material that these air ducts
use. For example, if I select this, and I
can see that the element in the
materials is air ducts B, I can go ahead
and select air ducts B,
toggle receive SSR, and I can do the same
with these
materials as well.
Enable SSR on all of these air duct
materials.
And now if I go into my volume here, and I
start messing
around with the screen space reflection
settings, I can start getting these air
ducts to reflect light using the scene
itself rather
than reflection probes. We can change the
amount of
smoothness. Minimum smoothness determines
how smooth an object must
be for SSR to be applied. Objects below
this minimum use
another reflection method such as
probes. The smoothness fade start will set
the smoothness
value at which SSR reflections begin to
fade
out. Lower values results in HDRP fading
out SSR reflections
for less smooth game objects. We have some
other settings here
such as the ability to reflect the sky,
the screen edge fade distance,
as well as the object thickness. This
controls how thick objects are
inside of your scene. So if I set this
thickness to one, we'll
see more reflections on our ducts here
because the rays
are not passing through them as much.
Additionally, we also have some quality
settings here, so I can set this to high
quality to get a bit of a better
reflection.
And we can also change the algorithm as
well. From approximation to PBR
accumulation. Approximation is a quicker
algorithm which results in
less resources used, but it's not as
accurate for rough
surfaces. Something like PBR accumulation
accumulates multiple
frames to generate a more accurate
result. And we can control the amount of
accumulation using this accumulation
This gives a more accurate result, but it
is more resource intensive
and it can lead to some ghosting. used on
Additionally, this algorithm cannot be
transparent materials as those will always
use
approximation. In the next module, we'll
begin talking about the basics of lighting
inside of HDRP by learning about the
different light types.