In this video, we're going to explore the
HDRP pipeline asset and how
you can use that to adjust settings inside
of your HDRP
project. To access the current pipeline
asset, we can go to edit, project
settings, and inside of the graphics tab
here, we can set the default render
pipeline
asset. This is going to be the default
asset that is used if you do
not assign individual pipelines inside of
the quality
tab. So you can see here we have all of
these different quality
levels. We have high fidelity, balanced
and
performant, and each has a slot for a
render pipeline
asset. So you can customize the settings
of your project based
on the quality level that you would
like. So for example, let's say that the
high fidelity quality level
here has a render pipeline asset with ray
tracing
enabled. Whereas the performant level has
a different pipeline
asset with ray tracing
disabled. However, if a quality level does
not have a render pipeline
asset assigned and we have that quality
level
selected, it's going to fall back on this
pipeline asset
here. We can select this asset inside of
our assets tab
by clicking the pipeline asset, and then
we will be directed to
the folder with the asset
itself. So here we have our HD render
pipeline
asset, as well as some global settings and
some default
volumes. We can create a new pipeline
asset by right
clicking, create, rendering, and then
select
HDRP asset. I'm going to select this and
call this
high fidelity. I'm going to command D to
duplicate
this and name this performant. And I'm
going to
command D and name this
balanced. And now I can go into
edit, project settings, quality, and
assign
all of my assets to these quality
levels. So I'm going to start with high
fidelity and we'll see it
right here. I'm going to repeat this step
with balanced.
And I'm also going to repeat this step
with performant.
And for now I'm just going to leave my
project on
balanced. And let's select the balanced HD
render pipeline asset.
Inside of a pipeline asset, we can see all
of these settings that have
to do with rendering, lighting,
materials, post processing, volumes, XR,
and
virtual texturing. We're going to go over
a lot of these features in
this course. We're not going to have time
to go through all of these
settings here, but there are a couple of
settings that we are going to
look at. We have some settings to enable
ray
tracing, enable the GPU resident
drawer, which can help speed up the
performance of your game by
drawing more frames on the
GPU. We can enable decals inside of our
game, enable dynamic resolution, which
allows you to use upscaling
to boost the frame rate of your
game. We can enable water as well as some
other
settings here. For lighting, we can make
sure that volumetric
fog is enabled, as well as making sure our
light probe system is on
adaptive probe volumes.
Making sure that screen space reflections
is
enabled, since we're going to be using
that later.
As well as enabling screen space
shadows, and we can also go through and
adjust some of these other
settings as well. Now these are settings
that are going to be specific
to just this render pipeline
asset. So for example, if you wanted to
turn off screen spacing
ambient occlusion or screen space global
illumination on this
asset, but you want that enabled for your
high fidelity
asset, you can do that as
well. The HD render pipeline global
settings asset
is going to allow you to change the
default settings of your
project. More specifically, you can change
all of these settings
inside of the volume here. So we can
change settings with the
exposure, with fog, the visual environment
such as the sky
type, and more. I'm going to close out of
this window.
Before I forget, let me also enable ray
tracing inside of this
project, since we are going to be
exploring ray
tracing. However, do be aware that for
this
course, in order to be able to use ray
tracing, you must be on a device that
supports ray
tracing. Such as DirectX 12
devices, which would be a Windows
computer, a PlayStation 5, or an Xbox
Series
X. You may not be able to see the results
of that ray
tracing. You can still implement
them, but Unity won't be able to render
it. In the next video, we're going to talk
about volume profiles and
how we can use that to adjust the settings
of our render pipeline
asset even more.